Kristin Zentner

+1-949-228-5821 | kristi.zentner17@gmail.com | Irvine, CA, 92614 www.kristizentner.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A software engineer with 2+ years professional experience supporting dynamic engineering teams. A quick learner, with strong communication and teamwork skills and well-versed in developing within an agile environment. Proven experience designing, developing and debugging full stack applications, with a heavy emphasis on React, JavaScript and front end development.

EXPERIENCE

Front End Engineer, Hawker Software

Jan 2023 - present

- Enhanced the React frontend's reliability with a Ruby-based end-to-end testing suite, resulting in a test coverage increase of over 30%
- Built a robust reporting feature capable of processing large amounts of data, offering 3 distinct report templates, to cater to diverse analytics needs
- Collaborated with executive leadership and backend engineers to ensure streamlined planning, development, and delivery of client-focused features
- Managed the lifecycle of new features, tech debt, and bug resolutions across the stack using
 agile methodologies and UI/UX design principles, prioritizing product stability and timely releases
- Dedicated 70% of work time to front-end development and 30% to backend tasks

Software Engineer II, Array

Aug 2022 - Jun 2023

- Developed a full-stack web-based UI/UX design application in Svelte and Node.js that streamlined the client onboarding process by reducing the workload of design and engineering teams
- Delivered 3+ long-term projects aimed at improving our product suite, including the creation of new embeddable web components
- Mentored and guided junior engineers by providing regular one-on-one assistance to solidify best practices and overall knowledge of important programming principles
- Contributed to the maintenance and improvement of existing code through debugging, regular testing, and identifying areas for optimization

Software Engineer I, Array

Mar 2022 - Aug 2022

- Collaborated across product, design, and engineering teams to maintain a suite of over 10
 embeddable and independently functioning web components written in Svelte, accessed by
 hundreds of thousands of users daily
- Implemented a comprehensive end-to-end testing suite with Playwright, which streamlined the QA process, reduced front-end related production bugs, and improved release quality
- Participated in daily code reviews with both senior and junior engineers to maintain elegant, efficient and dry code

EDUCATION

Fullstack Web Development Bootcamp, Honors Graduate

Aug 2021 - Jan 2022

NuCamp Coding Bootcamp

SKILLS

React, Node.js, Next.js, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Git, Redux, Ruby on Rails, Svelte, Agile and scrum methodology